Guide to the Mary Wilhelmine Williams Papers, 1911-1943
Department of Special Collections
Mary Wilhelmine Williams Papers,
1911-1943
Special Collections M0047
Williams, Mary Wilhelmine, 1878-1944
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Dr. Mary Williams, 1944
Biography
Mary Wilhelmine Williams was a professor of history, author, and authority on Latin America and inter-American relations.
Scope and Content
Letters, diaries, clippings, and manuscripts pertaining to Dr. William's interest in the Kensington Stone, education in Latin America, the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, and Dom Pedro of Brazil. Includes manuscripts of Dr. Williams' writings as well as reviews.
Access terms
Brainerd, Heloise; Hull, Cordell, 1871-; Lindbergh, Anne M., 1906-; Williams, Mary Wilhelmine, 1878-1944; American Historical Association; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom; Kensington Rune Stone; Latin America; Pan-Americanism
Container List
- Letters
  - Covering letter from Hoover Institution (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1936 - 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - a) Inter-American Cooperation
    - b) Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, U.S. Section
  - Letters, 1934 - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - a) State Department (convention for the promotion of Inter-American Cultural Relations)
    - b) Columbus Memorial Lighthouse
  - Letters regarding Dr. Williams' book, "Dom Pedro the Magnanimous" 1932 - 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photographs (in Photofile)
  - Photographs for Dr. Williams' book on "Dom Pedro the Magnanimous" (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters and photos regarding "Dom Pedro the Magnanimous," 1932 - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous reviews, blurbs, reprints, and articles by and about Dr. Williams. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Travel Diaries and Letters
  - Letters while in Latin American on a special educational survey for the American Association of University Women, 1926 - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Diaries: Vols. 1-2 of Latin American trip, 1926 -1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Diaries: Vols. 3-4 of Latin American trip, 1926 - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Diaries: Vol. 5 of Latin American trip, and trip to Mexico (6 vol.), 1926 - 1927, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters from H.R. Holand regarding the Kensington Stone Controversy, 1921 - 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Diaries of trip to England, and Triangular trip, 1911 - 1912, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous group of incoming letters, including one from Anne M. Lindbergh, 1916 - 1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Letters regarding meeting of American Historical Association, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts of articles, 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts of articles, 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Degree certificate -- Stanford University, Doctoral Philosophy (Box 3, Folder 7)